crittercism.com 2015-09-26

# Crittercism, Inc. Privacy Policy - Crittercism

Crittercism, Inc. takes your privacy seriously. We recognize that privacy is an important issue, so we design and operate our website and services with the protection of your privacy in mind. This Privacy Policy covers the collection of your Personal Information through your use of our website located at www.crittercism.com (collectively, the “Site”), through your use of our products and services made available through the Site, and through your use of our mobile application. This Privacy Policy also describes our use and disclosure of such information. The terms “Crittercism,” “we,” “our,” and “us” refer to Crittercism, Inc. The terms “you” and “your” refer to the user accessing or using the Site or the Services.

The term “Personal Information” as used in this Privacy Policy refers to personally identifiable information (PII) that specifically identifies an individual (such as an individual’s first and last name, address, telephone number, e- mail address, IP address, credit card or other account number), and any information directly linked to personally identifying information. Personal Information does not include aggregated information or other non-personally identifiable information.

Aggregate information is data we collect about a group or category of users that is not personally identifiable, or from which individual identities are removed and combined with others. We may collect, use and disclose aggregate information, and other non-personally identifiable information, for various purposes.

Crittercism has received TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. Please click [here](http://www.truste.com/about-TRUSTe/contact-us) for fax and postal mail information.

The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through the English edition of this Web Site, Crittercism’s online platform, and mobile application. TRUSTe’s certification does not cover information that may be collected through community.crittercism.com or any software downloaded from the Site.

## How We Collect Personal Information

We collect Personal Information from you in the following ways.

**Via Registration**

We collect the Personal Information you provide to us when you register for an account on the Site, including:

  * Contact Information such as name, email address, mailing address, phone number
  * Unique Identifiers such as user name, account number, password
  * Preferences Information such as product wish lists, order history, marketing preferences

We also collect information about your business such as company name, company size, and business type.

**Via Correspondence**

If you contact us by e-mail, using a contact form on the Site, or by mail, fax, or other means, we collect the Personal Information contained within, and associated with, your correspondence.

**Via E-mail Newsletters**

We offer e-mail newsletters and digests on the Site. If you sign up to receive a newsletter from us, we collect your e-mail address.

**Via Surveys**

From time to time, we offer surveys to our users to solicit feedback of our products or services. If you choose to participate in these surveys either through the Site or via email, we collect any Personal Information you provide.

**Via User Profiles**

This Site allows you to create and update a user profile. If you choose to create a user profile, we will collect the Personal Information that you provide when creating or updating a user profile, such as:

  * Contact information, such as your name, email address, mailing address, and phone number
  * Demographic information, such as your language, location and birth date

Please note that this information will be accessible to other users and not all information is required to create and maintain a user account.

**Via Community Forums**

This Site allows you to engage with other users through community forums, post comments to forums, and upload your own content (“User Materials”). We collect the Personal Information you provide us while using these interactive features, including any User Materials you may upload.

**Mobile and Email Data Collection**

When you access the mobile application, we may automatically collect (a) the type of device used to access the application, (b) the identifier for any handheld or mobile device used to access the application, and (c) your interactions with the application and its content. We also may collect information regarding your interaction with e-mail messages, such as whether you opened, clicked on, or forwarded a message.

**Geo-location**

We do not ask for, access or track any location based information from your mobile device at any time while downloading or using our mobile application or Services.

**Third Party Data Collection**

Crittercism collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose Personal Information it processes. If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like our Clients to share your information with us for the use of our service, please contact the Client you interact with directly.

## How We Use Personal Information

We use Personal Information for the following purposes:

  * to provide product, services and information that you request
  * to improve, operate, and maintain our products, services, websites and other systems
  * to prevent fraudulent use of our products, services, websites and other systems
  * to prevent or take action against activities that are, or may be, in violation of our Website Terms of Use, our Service Terms and Conditions or applicable law
  * to tailor advertisements, content and other aspects of your experience on and in connection with the Site
  * to maintain a record of our dealings with you and for other administrative purposes.

We may also use Personal Information to contact you regarding products, services, and offers, both from us and our partners, that we believe you may find of interest. If you prefer not to receive marketing communications from Crittercism, please see the “Updating Your Information And Contact Preferences” section below.

**User Data Supplementation**

We may receive information about you, including Personal Information, from third parties. We may combine this information with other Personal Information we maintain about you. If we do so, this Privacy Policy governs any combined information that we maintain in personally identifiable format.

If we link or associate any information gathered through passive means from the Site with your Personal Information, or if applicable laws require us to treat any information gathered through passive means from the Site as Personal Information, we treat the combined information as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy. Otherwise, we use and disclose information collected by passive means from the Site in aggregate form or otherwise in a non-personally identifiable form.

## Collection Technologies

Crittercism and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

**Server Logs**

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include IP addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to tailor and improve the services, marketing, we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or Site functionality.

**Advertising**

We partner with a third party to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this Site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. We do not have access to, or control over, these third-party means of passive data collection.

**Opting Out**

Your web browser may enable you to block or disable cookies, HTML5 LSOs and similar technologies. Each browser is different so you should check with your browser provider to find out how to block or disable these technologies. However, because these technologies are used throughout our Site, disabling them may prevent you from using certain features of our Site.  
**HTML5 Local Storage**

Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our Site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs.

## HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we do not disclose or transfer Personal Information about you to any third party unless we have your express permission.

**Service Providers**

Crittercism may share Personal Information with its fulfillment, hosting, payment, or similar service providers. These companies are authorized to use your Personal Information only as necessary to provide their respective services to us. Crittercism requires each of its service providers to agree to maintain the confidentiality of your Personal Information.

We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and the service agreements with our Clients. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

**Corporate Affiliates**

We may share your Personal Information with our corporate affiliates, such as a subsidiary or parent corporation. Crittercism requires its corporate affiliates that receive your Personal Information to limit their use and disclosure of your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Mergers, Acquisitions, and Bankruptcy**

We may share your Personal Information with an acquirer, successor, or assignee, as part of any merger, acquisition, debt financing, sale of company assets, or similar transaction. We will notify you in advance if any transfer materially affects your privacy rights. We may also share your Personal Information in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership as one of our business assets.

**Public Areas**

Any information you provide in blogs, forums or similarly non-private areas of the Site may be read, collected, and used by others who access these areas, and this information is not Personal Information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy. To request removal of your Personal Information from these areas, please contact us at [privacy@crittercism.com](mailto:privacy@crittercism.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Frames and Masking**

Some of our pages utilize framing or masking techniques to serve content to from our service providers while preserving the look and feel of our Site. Please be aware that you are providing your Personal Information to these service providers who will process the information on behalf of Crittercism.

**Legal Disclaimer**

Crittercism may also disclose or transfer your Personal Information:

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, and
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

## Updating Your Information And Contact Preferences

You may update some of the information you provide to us as follows:

**Your Account Information**

If you have an account on the Site, we provide mechanisms for you to review and update certain Personal Information you provided to us. You may correct, update, or amend your information by making the change on our member information page. You may also delete/remove, ask to have it removed from a public forum, or testimonial on our Site or deactivate it by emailing us at [privacy@crittercism.com](mailto:privacy@crittercism.com) or by contacting us by postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

Crittercism has no direct relationship with the third-parties whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to Crittercism’s Client (the data controller). If the Client requests Crittercism to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 days.

**Information Retention**

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as reasonably useful for commercial purposes. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

We will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. Crittercism will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Your Contact Preferences**

If you receive commercial e-mail from us, you may unsubscribe at any time by following the instructions contained within the e-mail. You may also opt-out from receiving commercial e-mail from us, and any other promotional communications we may send you (e.g., by postal mail) by e-mailing us at [privacy@crittercism.com](mailto:privacy@crittercism.com) or by writing to us at the address given at the end of this policy. If you have a user account on the Site, you may also view and modify the frequency of promotional communications you receive from us. Additionally, even after you opt-out from receiving commercial messages from us, you will still receive administrative messages from us regarding your use of the Site and any products or services made available through the Site. If you wish to no longer receive administrative messages, please deactivate your account.

**Your Third Party Sharing Preferences**

You may also opt-out from sharing your Personal Information with third parties for our marketing or promotional purposes by emailing us at [privacy@crittercism.com](mailto:privacy@crittercism.com). Please be aware that opt-out requests may take up to 10 business days to process, and you may receive commercial e-mail from us during that period.

## Additional Information

**Links to Third Party Sites**

Our Website includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Crittercism. If you submit Personal Information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web Site you visit.

**Inter-Application Communication**

Our mobile application features an email function that uses information from your device’s email application. Please be aware that this functionality enables you to share your Personal Information with your email service provider and other third parties. Do not use this functionality if you do not want to share your Personal Information.

**Testimonials**

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our Site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@crittercism.com](mailto:privacy@crittercism.com).

**Social Media Features**

Our Web Site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook “Like” button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Single Sign-On**

You can log in to our Site using sign-in services such as Google Sign In or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain Personal Information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Google Sign In give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web Site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

## How We Protect Personal Information

The security of your Personal Information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information, such as your login credentials, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web Site, you can contact us at [privacy@crittercism.com](mailto:privacy@crittercism.com).

## Child Specific Terms

Crittercism understands that children’s privacy is important. The Site is not intended for use by children under 13 years of age, and we do not knowingly collect any Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If you believe that we may have collected any such Personal Information on the Site, please notify us at [privacy@crittercism.com](mailto:privacy@crittercism.com).

## International Visitors

Crittercism complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Crittercism has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Crittercism’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

## Changes To This Privacy Policy

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at[ privacy@crittercism.com](mailto:privacy@crittercism.com) or at 760 Market Street, Suite 1101, San Francisco, CA94102.
